<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Felix Eigenbrod on Laura Jane Graham</title>
    <link>/authors/felix-eigenbrod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Felix Eigenbrod on Laura Jane Graham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/felix-eigenbrod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale-dependency in drivers of outdoor recreation in England</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_pan/</guid>
      <description>Why do we want to visit places for outdoor recreation and how can we measure this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignoring the spatial structure of the sea cucumber Isostichopus fuscus distribution when granting quotas can be costly</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_ocma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_ocma/</guid>
      <description>There is an increasing demand for fisheries resources worldwide. The brown sea cucumber &lt;em&gt;Isostichopus fuscus&lt;/em&gt; is the most valuable species from the Eastern Pacific and it has been almost depleted due to overfishing. Here, we show that it is important to consider the spatial structure of &lt;em&gt;Isostichopus fuscus&lt;/em&gt; populations when granting quotas. Given the high levels of illegal fishing within the Gulf of California, it is imperative that quotas are based on the lower bounds of spatially explicit density estimates – along with increased surveillance and enforcement – if the long-term commercial sustainability of the fishery is to be maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating fine‐scale environmental heterogeneity into broad‐extent models</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_mee2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_mee2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analytical framework for spatially targeted management of natural capital</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_nsust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_nsust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>